Aleksandr Nikitin

Saint-Petersburg, Russia / remote

nktn.lx@gmail.com

(a) <u>@nktnlx</u>

+79675608829



Data Analyst / Product Analyst

Solid technical background. Hold a Master of Science (M.S.) degree in geoscience, majoring in Seismic Data Processing and Analysis. Had worked with geophysical data (processing, analysing and interpreting) for 12 year. Now I'm in transition to Data/Product Analytics. Find myself being constantly fascinated by insights Data can reveal.

Practising critical and business-oriented thinking. Love to plan and manage priorities. Know how to focus and get things done. Enjoy studying and advocate a continuous learning approach. Strong communication skills and a proficient English user (C1). Achieved the 7th place at the open Data Analyst 2021 competition held by <u>Career Factory</u>.

Technical Skills:

- Python, Pandas, Numpy
- Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly
- Git, Airflow
- SQL, ClickHouse, PostgreSQL
- scipy.stats, statsmodels
- A/B testing, bootstrap

- Tableau, Redash
- Product metrics
- Unit economics
- Stakeholder management
- Reporting and presentations
- MS Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Project

Projects

Video Games Sales Analysis, Yandex Praktikum, 2021

- **Skills:** data cleaning, data analysis, descriptive statistics, central limit theorem, hypothesis testing, data visualization.
- **Tools:** Python, Pandas, Numpy, scipy.stats, Seaborn, Matplotlib.
- **Results:** analytical review of a video games market for an online video games store. Revealed future-proof video games platforms and the most popular video games genres depending on the market's region. Defined the correlation between critics score and sales volumes. Articulated data-based business recommendations.
- GitHub repo: https://clck.ru/UwSmt

A/B tests, Data Analysis course by Tinkoff and Moscow State University, 2021

- **Skills:** loading data, plotting data distributions, hypothesis testing, Shapiro-Wilk normality test, paired t-test, non-parametric Mann-Whitney U test and proportions z-test.
- **Tools:** Python, Pandas, scipy.stats, statsmodels, Matplotlib.
- Results: hypothesis tests for:
 - difference of means,
 - statistical significant of an average check value,
 - advertisement e-mailing campaign conversion.
- GitHub repo: https://clck.ru/UwTxv

Analytical Dashboard [Tableau], karpov.courses, 2021

- **Skills:** customer interview, design, features and design approval, building the dashboard, finalization, alteration and approval.
- Tools: Tableau.
- Results: created an analytical dashboard that helps to pick the most profitable listings for renting business.
- Tableau Public: https://clck.ru/UwV6

Professional Experience

2015 - 2020: **Head of Department** → **CTO**, Geology Without Limits Group

- manage seismic data acquisition and processing projects
- · development of a new marine seismic data acquisition technology and recording units
- product management
- Kanban adoption

2010 - 2015: Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist → Lead Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist → Senior Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist, Seismo-Shelf LLC

- seismic data analysis and processing for local and international customers
- · data processing project management,
- new staff seismic data processing training

2008 – 2010: **Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist**, All-Russia Petroleum Research Exploration Institute (VNIGRI)

- seismic data analysis and interpretation
- seismogeological modeling activities and calculations of reserves

Education

Major in: Seismic Data Processing and Analysis, Department of geophysical and geochemical methods of exploration activities, Saint Petersburg State Mining University, 2010

Professional retraining

- «Data Analysis Course», karpov.courses, 5 months, June 2021
- «Data Analysis Course», Tinkoff and Moscow State University, 3 months, May 2021
- «Data Analyst Professional Development Programme», Yandex Praktikum & University 20.35), 2 months, March 2021
- «Data Science Math Skills», Coursera Duke University, 1 months, October 2020
- «Computer Science Career Path», Codecademy, 5 months, July 2020

Data Analysis Portfolio on GitHub

278 contributions in the last year

